SAM RAHA

Full Stack Developer

**** 07842 602888

@ sam.raha@hotmail.co.uk

♀ Leeds, UK

www.samraha.com

PROFILE

After a first-class Honours Degree in Finance and a 3-year career in the procurement industry, I've decided to change directions to follow my passion for web development. I've enjoyed learning full stack development for the past 8 months through online courses and articles, books and Meetup groups to improve myself to the best of my ability and it is now my main focus to contribute to and learn from a professional team of developers to advance my career to the next level.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Freelance

03/2019 – Present Leeds, UK samraha.com/#portfolio Web Development Projects:

- The Loose Cut: Designed and coded a front-end static landing page with multi device compatibility for an official Leeds and Reading Festival band using HTML, CSS & JavaScript. Exposure to domain hosting, client interaction/ communication and improved understanding of agile development phases such as implementing customer feedback queries until all functionalities are tested and complete.
- Face Detector App: A full stack application that uses a machine learning API to recognise faces. Created with ReactJS, CSS, NodeJS, PostgreSQL & Clarifai API and deployed with Heroku. It also utilises a sign in system secured with Bcrypt password hashing. The creation of this application greatly improved my understanding of how the front and back-end of a complex dynamic app are connected via a server.
- Gatsby Blog: A personal blog to share developer resources. Created with GatsbyJS, ReactJS, GraphQL & CSS and deployed via Netlify. This project taught me how to utilise one of the fastest static site generator frameworks to build a Progressive Web App with performance in mind.
- Robofriends: A fun front-end React app that displays a friends list with a search function. Created with ReactJS, CSS & Robohash API. This project exposed me to the difference between developing vanilla JavaScript and React applications through component management.

Senior Buyer

Dragados

07/2017 - 05/2019 London, UK https://tinyurl.com/DragadosBSCU <u>£600m London Underground Bank Station Capacity Upgrade Project:</u>

- > Serving as the direct report for the Apprentice Buyer in the team. This developed my discipline of emotional intelligence, active listening, development training skills and the necessary skills required to cater to staff with special needs, i.e. breaking down the work into smaller, more manageable chunks and avoiding multi-tasking to stay focused.
- Lead commodity buyer of IT Hardware/ Software, Electronics, Steel, Timber, Consumables and Plant with a total spend value of £10m.
- > Succeeded in a PM role for the implementation of a new asset management software by utilising Kanban for project completion.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Black Belt in Taekwondo

Achieved at 10 y/o, teaching me discipline and leadership skills Tough Mudder (Full Challenge)

Awesome team bonding activity that raised money for charity.

SKILLS

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript
ReactJS NodeJS Bootstrap
PostgreSQL Python
GatsbyJS Netlify Git
Photoshop CS6

EDUCATION

The Complete Web Developer in 2019 - Full Stack Development

Udemy- Zero to Mastery
01/2019 - 03/2019
Studying topics such as: How
the Internet Works, History Of
The Web, HTML5, CSS,
Bootstrap 4, JavaScript
ES6/ES7/ES8, React, Redux, Git
+ Github, Node.js, Express.js,

NPM, PostgresSQL, SQL &

Python.

First Class Accounting and Finance BSc (Hons) Degree

University of Brighton
09/2013 - 05/2017
Innovation in EBusiness &
Mobile Commerce, Statistics,
Financial Reporting Theory &
Practice, Taxation, Finance &
Investment Risk Management,
Economics & Supply Chain
Management.

Associate Levels

Notre Dame College 09/2011 - 06/2013

ICT - C

Business Studies - C English Language - C

Accountancy (AS) - C